<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Findy Agency</title><link>https://findy-network.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on Findy Agency</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://findy-network.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>GopherCon UK 2023</title><link>https://findy-network.github.io/docs/videos/gophercon-uk/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://findy-network.github.io/docs/videos/gophercon-uk/</guid><description/></item><item><title>CDK-based Continuous Deployment for OSS</title><link>https://findy-network.github.io/docs/videos/aws-community-day/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://findy-network.github.io/docs/videos/aws-community-day/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Introduction to Self-Sovereign Identity</title><link>https://findy-network.github.io/docs/videos/introduction-to-ssi/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://findy-network.github.io/docs/videos/introduction-to-ssi/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Hyperledger Global Forum 2022 Presentation</title><link>https://findy-network.github.io/docs/videos/hyperledger-forum/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://findy-network.github.io/docs/videos/hyperledger-forum/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Findy Agency Architecture</title><link>https://findy-network.github.io/docs/overview/architecture/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://findy-network.github.io/docs/overview/architecture/</guid><description>Overview of Findy Agency. See more detailed description in findy-agent documentation. The backend server of Findy Agency consists of three services:
core/findy-agent that handles all agent functionality including credential handling and Aries protocols vault/findy-agent-vault that maintains a database of agents&amp;rsquo; data. Currently vault has only GraphQL-interface for data queries, that is intended mainly for browser web wallet use. auth/findy-agent-auth that registers and authenticates all agency users. Reference web wallet implementation is a React app that utilizes standard WebAuthn protocol and browser capabilities to authenticate to backend.</description></item><item><title>First Steps with Findy Agency</title><link>https://findy-network.github.io/docs/getting-started/setup-agency/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://findy-network.github.io/docs/getting-started/setup-agency/</guid><description>Full Agency Setup Agency services can be setup easily locally using Docker. Check further instructions here. The instructions describe how to launch all the needed backend services in Docker containers together with a simulated ledger. There is also a native development setup instructions for web wallet application which will be needed in order to run web wallet application together with other agents.
Once you have the services running on your computer,</description></item><item><title>Test Coverage</title><link>https://findy-network.github.io/docs/slides/test-coverage/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://findy-network.github.io/docs/slides/test-coverage/</guid><description>GopherCon UK 2023, London Slides for GopherCon UK 2023, August 2023
Laura presenting at GopherCon UK 2023. Photo by GopherCon UK. FooConf 2023, Helsinki Slides for FooConf 2023, November 2023
Laura presenting at FooConf 2023. Photo by FooConf. GoLab 2023, Florence Slides for GoLab 2023, November 2023
Laura presenting at GoLab 2023. Photo by GoLab.</description></item><item><title>CDK-based Continous Deployment for OSS</title><link>https://findy-network.github.io/docs/slides/aws-meetup/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://findy-network.github.io/docs/slides/aws-meetup/</guid><description>Slides for Tampere AWS User Group Meetup, March 2023
Laura at AWS User Group Meetup (Photo by Harri Lakkala)</description></item><item><title>Introduction to Self-Sovereign Identity</title><link>https://findy-network.github.io/docs/slides/introduction-to-ssi/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://findy-network.github.io/docs/slides/introduction-to-ssi/</guid><description>Slides for Digital Identity Hack 2023 Kick-off
Presentation
Harri Lainio introducing SSI</description></item><item><title>Hyperledger Global Forum 2022</title><link>https://findy-network.github.io/docs/slides/hyperledger-forum-2022/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://findy-network.github.io/docs/slides/hyperledger-forum-2022/</guid><description>Slides for Hyperledger Global Forum 2022 breakout session
Presentation</description></item><item><title>Findy Agency Presentation</title><link>https://findy-network.github.io/docs/videos/presentation/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://findy-network.github.io/docs/videos/presentation/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Configuration</title><link>https://findy-network.github.io/docs/deployment/configuration/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://findy-network.github.io/docs/deployment/configuration/</guid><description>Overall Findy Agency Deployment Architecture Internet-facing reverse proxy Nginx, AWS load balancer etc. can work as a reverse proxy. It is recommended to use single domain for request routing to avoid hassle with FIDO2 origin requirements and CORS.
Port 443 Path Target Note / pwa Static html /query vault GQL queries from PWA. Websocket support needed. /register, /login auth Webauthn requires HTTPS. Domain needs to match with PWA. /a2a agency Endpoint can be set with the agency&amp;rsquo;s start up flag.</description></item><item><title>Service Agents</title><link>https://findy-network.github.io/docs/getting-started/service-agent/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://findy-network.github.io/docs/getting-started/service-agent/</guid><description>Service agents i.e. organization agents utilize Findy Agency through its gRPC API. The agent creation and authentication is handled through the headless authenticator, acator, that implements the FIDO2 protocol. Once authenticated, all agent functionality is available to service agents via the core gRPC API, findy-agent-api.
Read more about getting started with service agents from the blog:
Getting Started with SSI Service Agent Development How to Equip Your App with VC Superpowers You can use our helper libraries for go, Typescript or Kotlin or use directly the gRPC interface with the language of your choice.</description></item><item><title>Demo: Alice-Faber-Acme</title><link>https://findy-network.github.io/docs/videos/faber-acme-demo/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://findy-network.github.io/docs/videos/faber-acme-demo/</guid><description>See description and instructions here</description></item><item><title>Demo: Findy Bots</title><link>https://findy-network.github.io/docs/videos/findy-bots/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://findy-network.github.io/docs/videos/findy-bots/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Interoperability Testing Demo</title><link>https://findy-network.github.io/docs/videos/interoperability/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://findy-network.github.io/docs/videos/interoperability/</guid><description>Test 1: Findy Agency based issuer/verifier with Lissi Wallet
A Findy Agency utilizing issuer tool invites Lissi Wallet to form a pairwise connection. Issuer tool sends and verifies a credential with Lissi Wallet.
Test 2: Findy Agency Web Wallet with Trinsic Wallet
Findy Agency Web Wallet user forms a pairwise connection with Trinsic Wallet user. Wallet applications send Aries basic messages to each other.
Test 3: ACA-Py based issuer/verifier with Findy Agency Web Wallet</description></item><item><title>SSI-Empowered Identity Provider</title><link>https://findy-network.github.io/docs/videos/oidc-provider/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://findy-network.github.io/docs/videos/oidc-provider/</guid><description>Open ID Connect (OIDC) is a popular identity protocol for authenticating users and providing identity data for access control. It allows web services to externalize the authentication of end-users by securely signing users in using a third-party identity provider. Findy Agency team has experimented with integrating SSI (self-sovereign identity) agent capabilities to a sample OIDC provider, thus enabling verified data usage in the login flow. The proof-of-concept shows that this approach would allow numerous web applications to switch to SSI-based login with minimal changes.</description></item><item><title>FTN Issuer Demo</title><link>https://findy-network.github.io/docs/videos/ftn-service/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://findy-network.github.io/docs/videos/ftn-service/</guid><description>A shortcut for SSI adoption is to use existing APIs when issuing credentials and build so-called self-service issuers. In this demo, we showcase how to implement a service for issuing credentials for Finnish Trust Network data.
Read more</description></item><item><title>The Swiss Army Knife for the Agency Project, Part 3: Other GitHub Tools</title><link>https://findy-network.github.io/blog/2024/04/24/the-swiss-army-knife-for-the-agency-project-part-3-other-github-tools/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://findy-network.github.io/blog/2024/04/24/the-swiss-army-knife-for-the-agency-project-part-3-other-github-tools/</guid><description>This post concludes the article series that overviews how our open-source project utilizes the GitHub platform for software development. In this last part, we will examine documentation, communication tools, and some utilities that help the development process.
GitHub Pages Already in the early days, when we started to experiment with SSI technology, there arose a need to publish different experiment outcomes and findings to the rest of the community. However, we were missing a platform to collect these various reports and articles.</description></item><item><title>The Swiss Army Knife for the Agency Project, Part 2: Release Management with GitHub</title><link>https://findy-network.github.io/blog/2024/04/23/the-swiss-army-knife-for-the-agency-project-part-2-release-management-with-github/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://findy-network.github.io/blog/2024/04/23/the-swiss-army-knife-for-the-agency-project-part-2-release-management-with-github/</guid><description>This article will examine how we handle releasing and artifact delivery with GitHub tools in our open-source project. When designing our project&amp;rsquo;s release process, we have kept it lightweight but efficient enough. One important goal has been ensuring that developers get a stable version, i.e., a working version of the code, whenever they clone the repository. Furthermore, we want to offer a ready-built deliverable whenever possible so that trying out our software stack is easy.</description></item><item><title>The Swiss Army Knife for the Agency Project, Part 1: GitHub Actions</title><link>https://findy-network.github.io/blog/2024/04/22/the-swiss-army-knife-for-the-agency-project-part-1-github-actions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://findy-network.github.io/blog/2024/04/22/the-swiss-army-knife-for-the-agency-project-part-1-github-actions/</guid><description>Our research project has been utilizing GitHub tools for several years. Most of the features are free for publicly hosted open-source projects. We have used these tools with an experimental spirit, gathering experience from the different features. Although our project does not aim directly at production, we take a production-like approach to many things we do.
In this article series, I summarize our team&amp;rsquo;s different experiments regarding GitHub features. As GitHub&amp;rsquo;s functionality is easily extensible through its API and abilities for building custom GitHub actions, I also explain how we have built custom solutions for some needs.</description></item><item><title>Issuing Chatbot</title><link>https://findy-network.github.io/blog/2024/04/11/issuing-chatbot/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://findy-network.github.io/blog/2024/04/11/issuing-chatbot/</guid><description>This post is a development story (or hands-on workshop) of how we can use an FSM chatbot to implement SSI Services to allow any SSI/DID owner to be an issuer. Let’s start with the result and see what the state machine looks like. As you can see below, it’s simple, elegant, and, most importantly, easy to reason.
Issuing Service Chatbot As you can see from the diagram there are two main paths.</description></item><item><title>I want mDL!</title><link>https://findy-network.github.io/blog/2024/04/06/i-want-mdl/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://findy-network.github.io/blog/2024/04/06/i-want-mdl/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s funny that we don&amp;rsquo;t have a mobile driver&amp;rsquo;s license in Finland. In the Nordics, we are usually good with digital and mobile services. For example, we have had somewhat famous bank IDs from the early 90s.
For the record, Iceland has had a mobile driver&amp;rsquo;s license since 2020. Surprise, Finland was in the pole position in the summer of 2018. The government-funded mobile driver&amp;rsquo;s license app (beta) was used with 40.</description></item><item><title>Managing GitHub Branch Protections</title><link>https://findy-network.github.io/blog/2024/03/27/managing-github-branch-protections/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://findy-network.github.io/blog/2024/03/27/managing-github-branch-protections/</guid><description>GitHub has recently improved its automatic pull request handling and branch protection features. I have found these features handy, and nowadays, I enable them regardless of the project type to help me automate the project workflows and protect the code from accidental changes and regression bugs.
The features I find most useful are
Require a pull request before merging: This setting enforces a model where the developers cannot accidentally push changes to the project&amp;rsquo;s main branches.</description></item><item><title>Path to Passwordless</title><link>https://findy-network.github.io/blog/2024/01/05/path-to-passwordless/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://findy-network.github.io/blog/2024/01/05/path-to-passwordless/</guid><description>Passkeys and security keys have gained more and more popularity lately, and no wonder – they provide much more security and usability than passwords. These authentication methods utilize strong and phishing-resistant public key credentials that the keys or authenticators, as we call them, can create automatically. However, implementing passwordless support in your web application, or even replacing passwords altogether, might initially seem overwhelming.
FIDO2 and WebAuthn Standards Ease the Job Integrating the authenticators into your web application happens through common standards created by the FIDO alliance.</description></item><item><title>Test Coverage Beyond Unit Testing</title><link>https://findy-network.github.io/blog/2023/11/16/test-coverage-beyond-unit-testing/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://findy-network.github.io/blog/2023/11/16/test-coverage-beyond-unit-testing/</guid><description>Automated testing is your superpower against regression. It prevents you from breaking existing functionality when introducing new code changes. The most important aspect of automated testing is automation. The testing should happen automatically in the continuous integration (CI) pipeline whenever developers do code changes. If the tests are not passing, the team shouldn&amp;rsquo;t merge the changes to the main branch. I often regard the automated test set as an extra team member – the team&amp;rsquo;s tireless knight against regression.</description></item><item><title>How To Write Modifiable &amp; Readable Go Code</title><link>https://findy-network.github.io/blog/2023/10/22/how-to-write-modifiable-readable-go-code/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://findy-network.github.io/blog/2023/10/22/how-to-write-modifiable-readable-go-code/</guid><description>Since jumping on the OSS (Open Source Software) wagon, I have been learning new things about software development and getting more evidence to do certain things in a specific way.
Two of my favorite &amp;rsquo;things&amp;rsquo; at the code level are readability and modifiability. The latter is a very old friend of SW architecture&amp;rsquo;s quality attributes (Software Architecture in Practice, Len Bass, et al.). Still, it is not well aligned with the current practices and tools in the OSS scene because everything is so text-centric.</description></item><item><title>How To Write Performant Go Code</title><link>https://findy-network.github.io/blog/2023/10/08/how-to-write-performant-go-code/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://findy-network.github.io/blog/2023/10/08/how-to-write-performant-go-code/</guid><description>I suppose all of us programmers have heard of the infamous premature optimization:
Premature optimization is the root of all evil in programming.
Really? I don&amp;rsquo;t think so.
The full quote from the must-read The Art of Computer Programming by Donald Knuth:
The real problem is that programmers have spent far too much time worrying about efficiency in the wrong places and at the wrong times; premature optimization is the root of all evil (or at least most of it) in programming.</description></item><item><title>GopherCon UK 2023</title><link>https://findy-network.github.io/blog/2023/08/23/gophercon-uk-2023/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://findy-network.github.io/blog/2023/08/23/gophercon-uk-2023/</guid><description>At the beginning of this year, I set myself a target to speak at a Go programming language conference. There were several reasons to do so. Go has been one of my favorite tools for years, and I have longed for an excuse to join a Go event. Giving a speech was perfect for that purpose. Plus, I have multiple excellent topics to share with the community as we do open-source development in our project, and I can share our learnings along with our code more freely.</description></item><item><title>Beautiful State-Machines - FSM Part II</title><link>https://findy-network.github.io/blog/2023/06/22/beautiful-state-machines-fsm-part-ii/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://findy-network.github.io/blog/2023/06/22/beautiful-state-machines-fsm-part-ii/</guid><description>As I explained in my previous blog post, the idea of chatbots came quite naturally for our SSI development team. Think tanks or research labs are outstanding workplaces when you have something to chew. And how juicy topic the SSI has been, oh boy.
FSM chatbots started as a thought experiment, but now, when I think of the invention, it has been quite clever in foreseeing genuine user needs. It has lead us towards the following layer model.</description></item><item><title>The Agency Workshop</title><link>https://findy-network.github.io/blog/2023/06/13/the-agency-workshop/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://findy-network.github.io/blog/2023/06/13/the-agency-workshop/</guid><description>During the Findy Agency project, our development team initially placed greater emphasis on running and deploying the agency in terms of documentation. Due to this prioritization, instructions on building agency clients have gotten less attention. We have now fixed this shortcoming by publishing the agency workshop to educate developers on using, building, and testing agency clients.
Agency Clients What exactly is an agency client? A client is a piece of software operated by an entity with an identity (individual, organization, or thing).</description></item><item><title>The Time to Build SSI Capabilities Is Now</title><link>https://findy-network.github.io/blog/2023/06/09/the-time-to-build-ssi-capabilities-is-now/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://findy-network.github.io/blog/2023/06/09/the-time-to-build-ssi-capabilities-is-now/</guid><description>During hallway discussions with various teams and organizations in recent months, I have been surprised by the emphasis on the underlying technology in SSI implementations. Even non-technical folks are wondering, e.g., which credential format will overcome them all. Don&amp;rsquo;t get me wrong; it&amp;rsquo;s not that I don&amp;rsquo;t see the importance of choosing the most interoperable, best performant, and privacy-preserving cryptography. I am afraid more critical problems keep hiding when we concentrate only on technical issues.</description></item><item><title>Digital Identity Hack Part 3 – Introduction to SSI Presentation</title><link>https://findy-network.github.io/blog/2023/05/25/digital-identity-hack-part-3-introduction-to-ssi-presentation/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://findy-network.github.io/blog/2023/05/25/digital-identity-hack-part-3-introduction-to-ssi-presentation/</guid><description>The rise of self-sovereign identity (SSI) presents a groundbreaking opportunity for progress and expansion in the financial sector, with the capacity to reshape digital financial services, simplify transactions, and facilitate seamless interactions. To capitalize on this potential, OP Lab and the EU funded Powered by Blockchain project organized a seminar day and online hackathon, exploring the innovative power of SSI technologies and institutional decentralized finance, setting the stage for a safer, more inclusive, and more efficient worldwide financial ecosystem.</description></item><item><title>Digital Identity Hack Part 2 – Panel Discussion on Blockchain Projects</title><link>https://findy-network.github.io/blog/2023/05/23/digital-identity-hack-part-2-panel-discussion-on-blockchain-projects/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://findy-network.github.io/blog/2023/05/23/digital-identity-hack-part-2-panel-discussion-on-blockchain-projects/</guid><description>The emergence of self-sovereign identity (SSI) offers a revolutionary opportunity for innovation and growth in the financial world, potentially transforming digital financial services, streamlining transactions, and enabling seamless interaction. To harness this potential, OP Lab and the EU-funded Powered by Blockchain project recently held a seminar day and online hackathon to investigate the disruptive capabilities of SSI technologies and institutional decentralized finance, paving the way for a more secure, inclusive, and efficient global financial ecosystem.</description></item><item><title>Digital Identity Hack – Unlocking the Potential of SSI</title><link>https://findy-network.github.io/blog/2023/05/11/digital-identity-hack-unlocking-the-potential-of-ssi/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://findy-network.github.io/blog/2023/05/11/digital-identity-hack-unlocking-the-potential-of-ssi/</guid><description>The emergence of self-sovereign identity (SSI) technologies has the potential to revolutionize the digital landscape of the financial world, presenting unparalleled opportunities for innovation and growth. As SSI gains momentum, it can transform how we interact with digital financial services, streamline transactions, and enable seamless interactions between users and services. By embracing these cutting-edge technologies, we have the unique chance to actively shape the future of the global financial ecosystem, fostering a more secure, inclusive, and efficient digital environment for individuals and businesses alike.</description></item><item><title>Deploying with CDK Pipeline</title><link>https://findy-network.github.io/blog/2023/05/08/deploying-with-cdk-pipeline/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://findy-network.github.io/blog/2023/05/08/deploying-with-cdk-pipeline/</guid><description>My previous post described how we have been using the native AWS IaC tools for defining and updating our PoC environment infrastructure. The story ended with taking AWS CDK v2 in use and switching the deployment process on top of CDK pipelines. In this article, I will describe the anatomy of our CDK pipeline in more detail.
Watch my &amp;ldquo;CDK-based Continuous Deployment for OSS&amp;rdquo; talk on AWS Community Day on YouTube.</description></item><item><title>Agency's IaC Journey</title><link>https://findy-network.github.io/blog/2023/04/25/agencys-iac-journey/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://findy-network.github.io/blog/2023/04/25/agencys-iac-journey/</guid><description>In the early days of Findy Agency&amp;rsquo;s development project, it became evident that we needed a continuously running environment in the cloud to try out different proofs-of-concept (PoCs) and demos quickly and easily. As our team is small, we wanted to rely heavily on automation and avoid wasting time on manual deployments.
Setup Infra without a Hassle At that time, I was interested in improving my AWS skills, so I took the challenge and started working on a continuous PoC environment for our project.</description></item><item><title>No-Code SSI Chatbots - FSM Part I</title><link>https://findy-network.github.io/blog/2023/03/13/no-code-ssi-chatbots-fsm-part-i/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://findy-network.github.io/blog/2023/03/13/no-code-ssi-chatbots-fsm-part-i/</guid><description>In this blog post, I&amp;rsquo;ll explain the syntax of our chatbot language. The good news is that the language is simple, and we already offer some development tools like UML rendering. There&amp;rsquo;ll be a second post where we&amp;rsquo;ll dive deeply into the implementation details. Our ultimate goal is to find a proper model checker and theorem proofer for the correctness of the chatbot applications.
Our team got the idea of chatbots quite early after we started to play with verifiable credentials and SSI.</description></item><item><title>How to Equip Your App with VC Superpowers</title><link>https://findy-network.github.io/blog/2023/02/06/how-to-equip-your-app-with-vc-superpowers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://findy-network.github.io/blog/2023/02/06/how-to-equip-your-app-with-vc-superpowers/</guid><description>My previous blog post explained how to get started with SSI service agents using our CLI tool. But what about the next step, the integration into your application?
As I have previously described in my earlier blog post, Findy Agency API is the interface to Findy Agency for clients that wish to use the agency services programmatically. You can compile the gRPC API for multiple languages. However, the most straightforward is to start with the ones for which we provide some additional tooling: Go, Typescript (JavaScript), or Kotlin.</description></item><item><title>Getting Started with SSI Service Agent Development</title><link>https://findy-network.github.io/blog/2023/01/30/getting-started-with-ssi-service-agent-development/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://findy-network.github.io/blog/2023/01/30/getting-started-with-ssi-service-agent-development/</guid><description>In the new SSI world, we craft digital services according to the self-sovereign identity model. We will have applications that issue credentials for the data they possess and applications that can verify these credentials. The central entity is the digital wallet owner that can hold these credentials and present them when needed.
&amp;ldquo;Ok, sounds great!&amp;rdquo; you may think. &amp;ldquo;I want to utilize credentials also in my web application. But where to start?</description></item><item><title>Ledger Multiplexer</title><link>https://findy-network.github.io/blog/2022/09/30/ledger-multiplexer/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://findy-network.github.io/blog/2022/09/30/ledger-multiplexer/</guid><description>In this technical blog post, I&amp;rsquo;ll explain how I implemented a plugin system into our Indy SDK Go wrapper and then extended it to work as a multiplexer. The plugin system allows us to use a key/value-based storage system instead of the normal Indy ledger. And multiplexing extended the functionality to use multiple data sources simultaneously and asynchronously. For instance, we can add a memory cache to help Indy ledger, which has been proving to make a considerable difference in a multi-tenant agency that can serve thousands of different wallet users simultaneously.</description></item><item><title>The Hyperledger Global Forum Experience</title><link>https://findy-network.github.io/blog/2022/09/27/the-hyperledger-global-forum-experience/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://findy-network.github.io/blog/2022/09/27/the-hyperledger-global-forum-experience/</guid><description>Our team started utilizing Hyperledger technologies in 2019 when we began the experimentation with decentralized identity. Since then, we have implemented our identity agency with the help of two Hyperledger Foundation projects: Hyperledger Indy for implementing the low-level credential handling and Hyperledger Aries for the agent communication protocols specification.
The Dublin Convention Centre hosted the Global Forum. At the same time, the Open Source summit also took place at the same venue.</description></item><item><title>The Findy Agency API</title><link>https://findy-network.github.io/blog/2022/08/29/the-findy-agency-api/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://findy-network.github.io/blog/2022/08/29/the-findy-agency-api/</guid><description>The gRPC API serves the client applications. The Findy Agency clients can control their agents through the Findy Agency API over the high-performing gRPC protocol. The API design results from iterative planning and multiple development cycles. Initially, we implemented it using a custom protocol that utilized JSON structures and DIDComm as the transport mechanism. The initial design seemed like a good plan, as we got the chance to test the exact DIDComm implementation we were using to send the agent-2-agent messages (used in the credential exchange flows).</description></item><item><title>Trust in Your Wallet</title><link>https://findy-network.github.io/blog/2022/04/27/trust-in-your-wallet/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://findy-network.github.io/blog/2022/04/27/trust-in-your-wallet/</guid><description>Our previous post showed how to speed up the leap to the SSI world for existing OIDC clients, i.e., web services using external identity providers for their user authentication. Our demonstrated concept enabled users to log in to web services using credentials from their identity wallet.
We used an FTN credential in the demo. After reading the post and seeing the demo, you may have wondered what this FTN credential is?</description></item><item><title>SSI-Empowered Identity Provider</title><link>https://findy-network.github.io/blog/2022/04/07/ssi-empowered-identity-provider/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://findy-network.github.io/blog/2022/04/07/ssi-empowered-identity-provider/</guid><description>Utilizing SSI wallets and verifiable credentials in OIDC authentication flows has been an interesting research topic for our team already for a while now. As said, the OIDC protocol is popular. Countless web services sign their users in using OIDC identity providers. And indeed, it provides many benefits, as it simplifies the authentication for service developers and end-users. The developers do not have to reinvent the authentication wheel and worry about storing username/password information.</description></item><item><title>Replacing Indy SDK</title><link>https://findy-network.github.io/blog/2022/03/14/replacing-indy-sdk/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://findy-network.github.io/blog/2022/03/14/replacing-indy-sdk/</guid><description>Once again, we are at the technology crossroad: we have to decide how to proceed with our SSI/DID research and development. Naturally, the business potential is the most critical aspect, but the research subject has faced the phase where we have to change the foundation.
Our Technology Tree - Travelogue
Changing any foundation could be an enormous task, especially when a broad spectrum of technologies is put together. (Please see the picture above).</description></item><item><title>The Missing Network Layer Model</title><link>https://findy-network.github.io/blog/2022/03/05/the-missing-network-layer-model/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://findy-network.github.io/blog/2022/03/05/the-missing-network-layer-model/</guid><description>The W3C&amp;rsquo;s DID Specification is flawed without the network layer model.
You might think that I have lost my mind. We have just reported that our Indy SDK based DID agency is AIP 1.0 compatible, and everything is wonderful. What&amp;rsquo;s going on?
Well, let&amp;rsquo;s start from the beginning. I did write the following list on January 19th 2022:
Indy SDK doesn&amp;rsquo;t align the current W3C and Aries specifications.
Core concepts (below) as explicit entities are missing: DID method, DID resolving, DID Documents, etc.</description></item><item><title>Fostering Interoperability</title><link>https://findy-network.github.io/blog/2022/01/19/fostering-interoperability/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://findy-network.github.io/blog/2022/01/19/fostering-interoperability/</guid><description>Different services have different requirements and technical stacks; there are also multiple ways to implement the Aries agent support in an application. Some projects choose to rely on an Aries framework of a specific language and bundle the functionality within the service. Others might run the agent as a separate service or, as in the case of Findy Agency, as an agency that serves multiple clients.
Sending Aries basic messages between wallets from different technology stacks.</description></item><item><title>Anchoring Chains of Trust</title><link>https://findy-network.github.io/blog/2021/11/09/anchoring-chains-of-trust/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://findy-network.github.io/blog/2021/11/09/anchoring-chains-of-trust/</guid><description>You will notice a repetitive pattern once you start to play with public-key cryptography. Everything is about chains, or more precisely about the links in the chain. You build these links with public/private key pairs. Links are unidirectional, which means that if you must link or point both ways, you need to have two key pairs, one for each direction.
Crypto Chain with Authenticator In this blog post, we talk mostly about protocols built with asymmetric key pairs, but we can build immutable data structures like Merkle trees and blockchains with one-way functions as well.</description></item><item><title>The Arm Adventure on Docker</title><link>https://findy-network.github.io/blog/2021/09/20/the-arm-adventure-on-docker/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://findy-network.github.io/blog/2021/09/20/the-arm-adventure-on-docker/</guid><description>Since the Findy Agency project launched, Docker has been one of our main tools to help set up the agency development and deployment environments. First of all, we use Docker images for our cloud deployment. On a new release, the CI build pipeline bundles all needed binaries to each service image. After the build, the pipeline pushes Docker images to the GitHub container registry, from where the deployment pipeline fetches them and updates the cloud environment.</description></item><item><title>Travelogue</title><link>https://findy-network.github.io/blog/2021/09/08/travelogue/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://findy-network.github.io/blog/2021/09/08/travelogue/</guid><description>The success of our team is measured:
How well do we understand certain emerging technologies? How relevant they are to the business we are in? How much potential do they have for our company&amp;rsquo;s business? If you are asking yourself if the order of the list is wrong, the answer is, it is not.
We have learned that you will fail if you prioritize technologies by their business value too early.</description></item><item><title>Announcing Findy Agency</title><link>https://findy-network.github.io/blog/2021/08/11/announcing-findy-agency/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://findy-network.github.io/blog/2021/08/11/announcing-findy-agency/</guid><description>Findy Agency provides a Hyperledger Aries compatible identity agent service. It includes a web wallet for individuals and an API for organizations to utilize functionality related to verified data exchange: issuing, holding, verifying, and proving credentials. The agents hosted by the agency operate using DIDComm messaging and Hyperledger Aries protocols. Thus it is interoperable with other Hyperledger Aries compatible agents. The supported verified credential format is currently Hyperledger Indy “Anoncreds” that work with Hyperledger Indy distributed ledger.</description></item><item><title>Search Results</title><link>https://findy-network.github.io/search/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://findy-network.github.io/search/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>