<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Getting Started on Findy Agency</title><link>https://findy-network.github.io/docs/getting-started/</link><description>Recent content in Getting Started on Findy Agency</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://findy-network.github.io/docs/getting-started/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>First Steps with Findy Agency</title><link>https://findy-network.github.io/docs/getting-started/setup-agency/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://findy-network.github.io/docs/getting-started/setup-agency/</guid><description>Full Agency Setup Agency services can be setup easily locally using Docker. Check further instructions here. The instructions describe how to launch all the needed backend services in Docker containers together with a simulated ledger. There is also a native development setup instructions for web wallet application which will be needed in order to run web wallet application together with other agents.
Once you have the services running on your computer,</description></item><item><title>Service Agents</title><link>https://findy-network.github.io/docs/getting-started/service-agent/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://findy-network.github.io/docs/getting-started/service-agent/</guid><description>Service agents i.e. organization agents utilize Findy Agency through its gRPC API. The agent creation and authentication is handled through the headless authenticator, acator, that implements the FIDO2 protocol. Once authenticated, all agent functionality is available to service agents via the core gRPC API, findy-agent-api.
Read more about getting started with service agents from the blog:
Getting Started with SSI Service Agent Development How to Equip Your App with VC Superpowers You can use our helper libraries for go, Typescript or Kotlin or use directly the gRPC interface with the language of your choice.</description></item></channel></rss>